I haven't felt like this in a while.
X-Xin!
（貂(てん)）し… 信(しん)　誰だよ？ こいつ
Who is this guy?
（信）黙ってろ
Be quiet.
（ムタ）ふむ… お前だべな？
頭巾の刺客を斬ったのは
It was you, wasn't it?
The one who killed the hooded assassin.
What if I am?!
だったら どうだってんだよ？
I won't give you an easy death.
楽には殺さないべ
覚悟するべ 小僧っ子
Prepare yourself, youngster.
I get that you're mad I killed your friend, but you'd better quit.
友達やられて怒ってんだろうが
やめときな
おっさんじゃ俺に勝てねえよ
You can't beat me, old man.
You people from the State of Qin know nothing.
秦(しん)の国のヤツらは
何も分かってないべ
中でも
お前は ずぬけて頭が悪いべ
And you're the stupidest of them all by far.
First, Zhuxiong is not my friend.
まず 朱凶(しゅきょう)は友達じゃないべ
And also, killing you is an extremely easy task for Muta.
それに お前を殺すことなんて
ムタには とても簡単なことだべ
Like this, for example...
例えば こうだべ
Wh-What the hell?!
な… 何だ？
Ancient China.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望が解放されていた
human desire was unleashed.
And a storm of violent wars lasting a monumentally long 500 years erupted all across China.
激烈なる戦争と戦乱の嵐が―
500年という
途方もなく長きにわたって―
中国全土に吹き荒れていた
欲望 快楽 苦痛 恐怖…
Desire, pleasure, pain, fear.
With that world filled with such relentless despair, it was as though a dragon had invaded.
過酷で絶望に満ちた その世界には
竜がいたに違いない
A dragon called the "era".
“時代”という名の竜が
And as if burned by the flames of a dragon,
そして
竜の炎に焼かれるかのように―
over one hundred states were destroyed one by one until only seven were left standing.
100を超える国は 次々と滅び
今や ７国に淘汰(とうた)されていた
Yan, Qi, Zhao, Wei, Han, Chu...
燕(えん) 斉(せい) 趙(ちょう) 魏(ぎ) 韓(かん) 楚(そ)…
そして 秦である
and Qin.
The seven great powers, in order to devour each other,
７つの大国は おのおのが
おのおのを食らい尽くすように―
took up their swords of desire and continuously pieced the throats of enemy states.
欲望の剣を 敵国の喉元に向かって
突き立て続けた
The world knew it as the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
世にいう春秋戦国時代である
そして今 西の果て 秦の国から―
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the state of Qin in the far West.
大きな歴史の風が
吹き荒れようとしている
これは
戦乱の時代を走り抜いた―
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
Seboo
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuitous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
KoolKidsK
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Qpax
Now's the only time.
～♪
Unbreakable Heart
Mm. You have some talent for war.
ふむ… お前には武の才能があるべ
体が
自然とムタの毒矢に反応しているべ
Your body is responding naturally to Muta's poison arrows.
Poisoned arrows?
毒矢！
But rest assured.
だが 安心していいべ
朱凶を殺したお前に
吹き矢は使わないべ
Having killed Zhuxiong, Muta will not use a blowgun on you.
What?!
なに？
Honestly, Zhuxiong was someone who got on Muta's nerves.
朱凶は 実に頭に来るヤツだったべ
ムタの吹き矢を
卑怯(ひきょう)と言ってバカにしていたべ
He made fun of Muta, calling Muta's blowgun "cowardly".
ムタの強さを認めていなかったべ
He did not recognize Muta's strength.
The blowgun is a deadly weapon handed down through the Bessa Tribe of Koshi Province.
吹き矢は 越(えつ)の国のベッサ族に
伝わる必殺の武器だべ
But the people of Qin are stupid, so they don't understand that.
だけど 秦国のヤツらは
頭が悪くて それが分からないべ
If you don't understand, Muta can't help you.
分からないから しょうがないべ
Muta will just teach you his strength without using a blowgun.
吹き矢を使わないで
ムタの強さを教えてやるべ
With these axes, Muta will cut you, who was stronger than Zhuxiong, to pieces.
朱凶より強かったお前を
この まさかりでズタズタにして
ムタの圧倒的強さを
秦国のバカどもに教えてやるべ
And show to those Qin idiots Muta's overwhelming strength!
He's fast!
速(はえ)え！
Xin!
信！
（ムタ）ヤーッ！
But not as fast as me!
だが 速さなら負けねえ！
Xin!
信！
You bastard...
てめえ…
To not only dodge Muta's attacks, but to even wound him is quite surprising!
ムタの一撃をかわしたうえに
手傷を負わせるとは 驚いたど
As a warrior of the Bessa Tribe, Muta cannot overlook this.
ベッサ族の戦士として
これは ただでは済ませないど
On Muta's honor as part of the Bessa Tribe, he will rip out your entrails and kill you, youngster!
ベッサ族の誇りに懸けて
小僧っ子 貴様の内臓…
ぶちまけて殺すべ！
Just try it.
やってみろよ… 四角い おっさん！
Square old man!
You brat!
この小僧！
All three of the target heads have arrived.
標的の小首３つが そろったべな
Zheng! It's the pursuer!
政(せい)！ 追っ手だよ
It's Chengjiao's assassin! What're you doing just standing there and spacing out?
成蟜(せいきょう)の刺客だ
なに ボサッと突っ立ってんだよ？
早く加勢に行きなよ
信 やられちまうよ
You've gotta go help him!
Xin's gonna get killed!
Do you need a hand?
（政）手が必要か？
Like hell I do!
…なわけねえだろう
ア～ッ！ ちょっと待ってよ
Hold on a second!
あの変なおっさん
メチャクチャ強いんだって
That weird old man is insanely strong!
知っている　見ていたからな
I know. I've been watching.
But if he dies in a place like this,
だが こんな所で負けるようじゃ
for what we'll be facing later, no matter how many lives you have, it won't be enough,
この先 いくつ命があっても
足りないぞ 信
Xin!
No matter what you say, that guy is seriously dangerous.
そんなこと言っても
あいつ マジでヤバイぞ
ウワッ！ …つうか
小首３つって 俺も入ってる？
And is he including me when he says three heads?
ウウッ… 俺の首…
My poor head!
What? Are you still making fun of Muta?
なんだべ　お前ら
まだムタをバカにしてるべか？
頭に来るべ
That makes Muta angry!
He's coming!
来る
You've got good eyes, youngster!
目がいい小僧っ子だべ
What is this?!
何だ？ これ
Shit, I can't see!
くそ！ 見えねえ！
Got you!
もらったべ
Xin!
信！
グウッ…
グハッ！
ハァ… びっくりした
なんとか剣で防いだのか
That had me scared.
Somehow, he managed to block it with his sword.
Ow...
いってえ…
Are you weak?
弱いべか？
Huh? Something's odd.
（貂）あれ？ 何か変だ
Right now, Xin has sort of lost his edge...
今の信 キレがないっていうか
He kinda seems smaller compared to when he was fighting Zhuxiong.
なんだか
朱凶と戦ったときより小さく見える
That's enough. This has started to get dull.
いいかげん面倒くさくなってきたべ
Die!
死ね！
ウッ…
（政）下がるな 信！
Don't step back, Xin!
Step back? Me?
下がる？
俺が？
ビビってたってのか？ 俺が
Am I scared?!
Your weapon is your conviction!
不退転こそが お前の武器だ
I know that!
分かってらぁ！
グアッ！
あ… 相討ち　でも 信が変わった
They both hit...!
But Xin's changed!
He's been released from the curse of Muta's killing intent.
ムタの殺気の呪縛から解放されたな
The real battle will start here.
これからが本当の勝負だ
I'm sorry for calling you here so early in the morning,
（肆氏(しし)）早朝より お呼び立てして
心苦しいが
どうしても気がかりなことが
あったゆえ ご理解をいただきたい
but there's an worrisome matter at hand, so please understand.
General Wang Qi, we received from you last night
（肆氏）王騎(おうき)将軍
貴殿より 昨夜 届けていただいた
昌文君(しょうぶんくん)の首についてであるが
something in regard to Changwenjun's head, but...
The injury is brutal.
損傷が ひどく
昌文君本人との確認が取れませぬ
We cannot ascertain whether or not this actually Changwenjun.
So I ask you, could you tell us in detail in what kind of fight and in what way such a cruel event occurred?
昌文君と どのように戦い
どのようにして―
このような無残なこととなったか
詳しく お聞かせ願いたい
（王騎）ムフッ…
General Wang Qi.
王騎将軍
（王騎）おやぁ？
Oh?
（肆氏）何を…
What?
Do you doubt me, Shi Shi?
肆氏は
この王騎を疑っておいでですか？
う… 疑っているわけではござらん
It is not that I doubt you,
ただ 状況を把握しておくことが
私の務めです
it is merely my duty to have a firm grasp of the state of affairs.
（王騎）
ンフッ… そこまで言われては…
Well, if you're going that far...
いいでしょう
all right.
However, it's not a very interesting tale.
さして
面白い戦語りでもありませんが
（王騎）ンフッ…
Wait right there, Changwenjun!
お待ちなさい 昌文君
I'll stop Wang Qi.
王騎は わしが食い止める
お前たちは大王を守れ！
You all, protect the king!
My lord!
（兵士）殿！
Changwenjun!
（漂(ひょう)）昌文君！
Forgive me, Piao!
許せ 漂
So you've come, Changwenjun.
来ましたね 昌文君
ヌオーッ！
Wang Qi!
王騎！
ンフッ…
It sure is nostalgic, having our horses lined up side-by-side, Changwenjun.
こうやって馬を並べるなんて
懐かしいですね 昌文君
We're enemies now!
今は敵同士だ
懐かしんでなど いられるか！
There's nothing nostalgic about it!
ンフッ…
Wang Qi! I thought you had no interest in the struggle between Jie Shi and Lü Shi in the first place!
王騎！ そもそも
貴様は 呂氏(りょし) 竭氏(けつし)の争いに―
興味はなかったはず
なぜ突然 参戦してきた？
Why have you suddenly joined the battle?
熱き血潮 渦巻く戦いを求めて
I want a fight that will get my blood enflamed and pumping.
I don't understand you!
ワケが分からん！
I would think you would understand.
あなたなら分かるでしょう
（斬る音）
ヌオッ…
Since Lü Shi and Jie Shi took control the State of Qin,
（王騎）呂氏 竭氏が
牛耳る秦国になってから―
戦争は 恐ろしく
つまらないものになりました
war has become a dreadfully dull affair.
昭王(しょうおう)の時代が
懐かしくて たまりませんねえ
I couldn't help but feel nostalgic for the age of Zhao.
分かるでしょう？ この気持ち
Don't you understand those feelings?
（昌文君）
フン… 確かに 今日(こんにち)の戦は―
It's true that money and goods in today's battles frequently get moved behind the scenes, directly profiting Lü Shi.
裏で金品が回り 呂氏の利益に
直結することも しばしば
But that has nothing to do with all of you on the battlefield.
だが 戦場のお前たちには
関係のないことであろう
You jest.
ご冗談を… そんな不遜な戦争で
私の血がたぎるとでも思ってるの？
Do you think my blood would seethe...
for such an irreverent war?
My heart is quite delicate.
私の心は とても繊細なのよ
それでは わしのような
ただの文官と戦うことで―
So then fighting a civil official like me...
is what can get your blood seething?!
血がたぎるとでもいうのか！
ンフッ… 可能性はありますね
There's a possibility.
Long ago, we ran through the battlefield together.
かつては 共に戦場を駆け抜け―
気骨のある武人と
認めていましたからねえ
So I've recognized you as a soldier with backbone.
So the idea of fighting to the death with someone like you...
そのあなたと やり合えるなんて…
ヌオッ！
（王騎）久々に燃えそうでしょう？
gets me all fired up.
My lord!
（兵士）殿！
我らの勝ちだ 王騎
This is our victory, Wang Qi!
We've made it!
着いたぞ　束逹(つかだち)の丘だ！
The Shuda Hills!
The Shuda Hills? What are they?
（肆氏）束逹の丘？ 何だ？ それは
それから どうなったのだ？
What happened then?!
ンフッ…
実に あの男らしい やり口でした
It was actually a method that seemed quite appropriate for that man.
束逹の丘… 兵を隠しておくには
絶好の場所でしてね
The Shuda Hills. It was an excellent place to hide soldiers.
That's right, Wang Qi!
そのとおりだ 王騎
First squadron, second squadron, protect the king's coach!
（指揮官Ａ）第１軍 第２軍は
大王の御車を守れ！
Third squadron, fourth squadron, assist the lord!
（指揮官Ｂ）
第３軍 第４軍は 殿を助けよ！
So Changwenjun had mobilized his personal army there?
昌文君
私兵を総動員したというわけか
But what did you do in such a situation?
しかし
そのような状況で どうやって？
Is it not obvious?
決まってるじゃありませんか
The Shuda Hills are an excellent place to hide soldiers.
束逹の丘 兵を隠すには絶好の場所
So I had my own forces stationed there as well.
こちらも
伏兵を用意していましたからねえ
Wh-What?!
な… なにぃ！
Nooow then, Changwenjun!
（王騎）さあ 昌文君
The fighting begins!
合戦ですよ
And you and I can fight one-on-one!
そして
あなたは この私と一騎打ちですよ
And so... the result of that is what I have given you.
（王騎）
まあ その結果が お渡しした それ
I'm sorry it was so much that his face became unrecognizable.
顔も分からないほどにしたのは
悪かったけど
でも この王騎と戦ったら―
But when you're fighting with me, Wang Qi, your head usually doesn't get out looking unscathed.
大抵 メチャクチャな首に
なっちゃうでしょう
If you think I am lying,
ウソだと思うんなら…
Shall I test this out on a head around here?
その辺の首で
試してさし上げましょうか？
May I ask one thing?
ひとつ お伺いしても よろしいか？
As many as you like.
いくらでも
What is it you desire at this moment, General Wang Qi?
王騎将軍は今
何を望んでおられますか？
あなたほどの方が―
I cannot imagine that someone of your caliber would assist us merely for Changwenjun's territory.
昌文君の領地欲しさに
我らに加担するとは思えませぬ
A world of seething blood and dancing flesh.
血湧き肉躍る世界
Or at the least, a battle that gets my blood enflamed and pumping!
さもなくば…
熱き血潮 渦巻く戦い
Just kidding.
な～んちゃって
もう そんな世界
あるわけがありません
Such a world no longer exists.
だけど…
But...
If such a world were to appear in the future,
もし これから
そんな世界が来るとしたら―
I wouldn't be able to resist it.
たまりませんねえ
I found it!
（兵士Ａ）あったぞ！
No doubt about it.
（隊長）
間違いない　これは あのムタの物
This belongs to that man, Muta.
He's close.
（隊長）近いな　よし このまま…
Okay, let us continue...
Captain. What is it?
（兵士Ｂ）隊長 どうされました？
気のせいか… 行くぞ
Perhaps my imagination...
Let's go!
Captain!
隊長！
What?!
何だ？
（兵士）山の民か！
Mountain People?!
敵だ！
（兵士）どこだ？
Enemies!
Where?!
違う！ 兵士だ！
No!
They're soldiers!
Ridiculous!
バカな… こんな山中で敵兵など…
Enemy soldiers this deep in the mountains...?!
敵兵？ そもそも 我らに敵兵など…
Enemy soldiers?
But we don't have any enemies in the first place...
Y-You're...!
お… お前は…
Amazing! That Xin suddenly got stronger!
すげえ… 信のヤツ 急に強くなった
信は 朱凶のときは
怒りに我を忘れて戦った
When Xin fought Zhuxiong, he lost himself in anger.
He probably doesn't remember it that well himself.
恐らくは あいつも
よくは覚えていないだろう
Therefore, for him right now,
だから
今の戦いが あいつにとっては―
this may very well feel like his first serious fight to the death.
真剣での斬り合いの
初戦と言っていい
I get it...
そうか… これが ホントの初めて
This is his true first experience.
Apparently, he had over one thousand serious bouts with Piao.
（政）
あいつは 漂と本気で1,000を超えて
打ち合いをしていたらしい
（貂）1,000…
A thousand...?
Thanks to those, he possesses swordsmanship even greater than those military warriors.
（政）
おかげで そこいらの武人には
負けない剣技を持っているが
But there's one area he hasn't cultivated.
培われていないものが ひとつある
The emotional strength to repel a killing intent aimed at him.
自分に向けられた殺気を
跳ね返す精神力だ
But Xin realized that he was being pressured and stepping back from that killing intent,
だが 信は 殺気に押されて
下がっていたことに気づき前に出た
and stepped forward.
That assassin is strong.
あの刺客も強いが
ここからの信も相当 やるぞ
But as he is now, Xin will give him a run for his money.
He can do it?
やるか… そうか やるか！
He really can?!
This youngster...
この小僧っ子
even after losing this much blood,
これだけ血を流しても
心が折れてないべ　それどころか…
his spirit still hasn't broken.
Far from that...
Far from that, he keeps coming and coming!
それどころか
前に 前に出てくるべ…
This guy is getting stronger and stronger!
こいつ どんどん強くなるべ…
What...?!
（信）何だ？
What is this?
何だ？ これ
（蹴る音）
ウワッ！
It feels like... my body's gotten lighter!
体が… 軽くなってきたみたいだぜ
This again?
また これか！
Your distractions won't work anymore!
もう目くらましは効かねえ！
はっきり見えてんぞ！
I can see you perfectly!
ヌオーッ！
（信）ヤーッ！
He's getting sharper and sharper!
こいつ どんどん鋭く…
ヤッ！
（ムタ）ウワッ！
この小僧っ子…
This youngster...
is a menace.
脅威だべ…
I did it...
やった…
I did it!
やったぞ
He won!
やった！
Don't push yourself too hard!
ムリすんな
今 傷の手当てをしてやるからな
Let me treat those wounds for you.
ベ… ベッサ族の戦士として
このままでは終われないべ
A-As a Bessa Tribe warrior, I cannot let it end this way.
At the very least, I'll have the king's life.
王さまの命だけでも
もらっていくべ…
Run, Zheng!
逃げろ 政！
Prepare yourself.
覚悟するべ…
ウワッ！
（信）ハッ…
What are you trying to do to my king?!
我が王に 何のマネだ？ 貴様！
You bastard!
ターッ！
（ムタ）ウワッ！
あっ… お前(めえ)は…
You're...
Xin!
（貂）信！
Even though I said, "the escape plan will work perfectly"...
（昌文君）脱出の手だては
万全と言っておきながら…
I will take full responsibility.
全ての責任は
この私によるものであります
If you command me to, I will crush my head with these stones and die.
仰せとあらば 今すぐ
この岩で 頭を砕いて果てまする
しかし…
But... But first and foremost... I'm so glad you're safe!
しかし まずは何よりも…
よくぞ ご無事で！
As I am for you.
（肩に手を置く音）
お前もな
My king...
（兵士）大王さま…
Cut the shit!
ふざけんじゃねえぞ！
（昌文君）うん？
What's there to be "glad" about?!
何が良かっただ…
てめえも… てめえも てめえも！
ふざけたこと言ってんな！
You... and you... and you...!
Are spouting a load of crap!
Hey, old man!
おい おっさん！
Piao is... Piao is...
漂は…
漂は死んだんだぞー！
Piao is dead!
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
～♪
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
Voice of soul
（信）教えてくれ　俺は
どうしたら将軍になれるんだ？
Voice of you
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）命を懸けて進むと決めた
友に誓った夢は 決して忘れない
I won't cry
次回 “大将軍への道”
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
Tell me. How can I become a general?
Preview
He has wagered his life to move forward.
And he will never forget the vow he made to his friend!
The Path to a Great General
Next time,
End